<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on KYANOS lab.</title>
        <link>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on KYANOS lab.</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Temperature and pressure forecasting program in Python</title>
            <link>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/2022/06/03/forecast/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/2022/06/03/forecast/</guid>
            <description>I feel headache and lethargy when the atmospheric pressure drops suddenly, so I created this app hoping to forecast the atmospheric pressure.
　There are many weather forecasting apps and services, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a free service that provides a relatively long-term (5 days) atmospheric pressure forecast.
　OpenWeatherMap is an overseas company, but it seems to cover Japanese cities to some extent.
　By specifying the obtained API key and the city name or latitude and longitude in the program, the graph of temperature and pressure is drawn.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>　I feel headache and lethargy when the atmospheric pressure drops suddenly, so I created this app hoping to forecast the atmospheric pressure.</p>
<p>　There are many weather forecasting apps and services, but I couldn&rsquo;t find a free service that provides a relatively long-term (5 days) atmospheric pressure forecast.</p>
<p>　OpenWeatherMap is an overseas company, but it seems to cover Japanese cities to some extent.</p>
<p>　By specifying the obtained API key and the city name or latitude and longitude in the program, the graph of temperature and pressure is drawn.</p>
<p><img src="/forecast.jpeg" alt="forecast images"></p>
<p>　By viewing this graph together with the temperature graph, we can predict that June 6 is likely to be a very stormy day with low temperatures and low pressure.</p>
<p>　We would like to add more functions such as displaying daily weather forecasts as icons, but we have uploaded the project to GitHub.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/1plus1is3/forecast">forecast</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>I started a blog</title>
            <link>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/2022/03/03/atfirst_en/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/2022/03/03/atfirst_en/</guid>
            <description>In February 2022, I launched my portfolio site while I was busy with the Applied Information Technology exam.
(The GitHub history is a bit strange because I updated it significantly in June 2022.)
　This is due to the fact that I was able to get a chance to stand up and meet with them. It was also a good opportunity to write code and use GitHub properly.
　The site has a fairly minimalist structure, with only the top page, an About page, and a Posts page, which is a blog.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>　In February 2022, I launched my portfolio site while I was busy with the Applied Information Technology exam.</p>
<p>(The GitHub history is a bit strange because I updated it significantly in June 2022.)</p>
<p>　This is due to the fact that I was able to get a chance to stand up and meet with them. It was also a good opportunity to write code and use GitHub properly.</p>
<p>　The site has a fairly minimalist structure, with only the top page, an About page, and a Posts page, which is a blog.</p>
<p>　On Twitter, I tweet about trivial matters, including daily life, and collect information.</p>
<p>　Qiita is used to share problem-solving records.</p>
<p>　I record my blog on this site as a way to show people (and look back on it myself) that I know what I&rsquo;m doing and what I&rsquo;m doing now.</p>
<h1 id="motivation">Motivation</h1>
<p>I am from the generation where the Corona Disaster hit job hunting, so I have never exchanged business cards properly as a member of society.</p>
<p>　When I was an M1 student, I was allowed to make business cards in the format designated by the school with the name of my laboratory on them, and I used to scatter them around whenever I attended events or met people from companies, but now that they are gone, I realize how great they are.</p>
<p>　Although there have been many analog matters that should be abolished in the wake of the Corona disaster, such as seals, I think business cards are useful, and I would like to see them revived if possible.</p>
<p>　So, even though I can&rsquo;t replace the business card itself, I decided that I would like to make &ldquo;this is who I am&rdquo; available online, and this portfolio site was born out of that desire.</p>
<p>　I feel that it is currently smart to send the URL of this site during a videoconference by chat, or to include the URL in an email or Twitter message.</p>
<h1 id="github-pages--hugo-as-an-option">GitHub Pages + HUGO as an option</h1>
<p>　Many people in the technical community use existing blogging services, and I have used them myself.</p>
<p>　However, in creating my own portfolio site</p>
<ul>
<li>URLs can be complicated</li>
<li>Limitations on page customization</li>
<li>Japanese service is not familiar to overseas users.</li>
</ul>
<p>　I felt these disadvantages, so I used a combination of GitHub Pages and HUGO (using the friend-hello-ng theme).</p>
<p>　The name is linked to the GitHub account, the theme can be pulled from the designer&rsquo;s GitHub or created by the designer himself, and the support for Japanese and English has solved the above demerits.</p>
<p>At first, I was considering GitLab Pages and Gatsby because of their reputation, but since I was still unfamiliar with GitHub Pages, I decided to go with GitHub Pages because it had more knowledge about troubleshooting, etc. Gatsby&rsquo;s themes are still relatively few and I felt they were more for designers, so I rejected the idea. It&rsquo;s not that it wasn&rsquo;t good, it&rsquo;s just that it wasn&rsquo;t suitable for me.</p>
<h1 id="what-i-am-currently-working-on-and-what-i-can-do">What I am currently working on and what I can do</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Python</p>
<ul>
<li>Displaying 5-day temperature and pressure graphs using OpenWeatherMap API, Pandas, and MatPlotLib</li>
<li>Creating an English vocabulary learning web application using Django (I plan to link it with heroku and make it fly from this site)</li>
<li>Machine learning using scikit-learn
<ul>
<li>I am still learning because I have a lot of prerequisite knowledge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>HTML&amp;CSS, PHP</p>
<ul>
<li>Web applications including vulnerabilities created in LAMP environment. I are planning to create an exchange bulletin board that can be browsed and written by registration only, and later on, I will use Burp Suite to perform vulnerability diagnosis and compile it into a report.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Security</p>
<ul>
<li>TryHackMe</li>
<li>HackTheBox</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Preparation for the Applied Information Technology Engineer Examination</p>
<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m planning to take the exam in October 2022.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="currently-interested-in-the-following-fields">Currently interested in the following fields</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Rust, C++</p>
<ul>
<li>Dazzled by the abundance of libraries and frameworks in Python, but basically do not like dynamically typed languages and prefer to use statically typed languages when I want to increase execution speed</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Mathematics</p>
<ul>
<li>Algebra</li>
<li>Algebraic geometry</li>
<li>I especially enjoy elliptic curves and Arbel&rsquo;s what-around.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>　That&rsquo;s all.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
