<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KYANOS lab.</title>
    <link>https://1plus1is3.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on KYANOS lab.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://1plus1is3.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and pressure forecasting program in Python</title>
      <link>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/2022/06/03/forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/2022/06/03/forecast/</guid>
      <description>I feel headache and lethargy when the atmospheric pressure drops suddenly, so I created this app hoping to forecast the atmospheric pressure.
　There are many weather forecasting apps and services, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a free service that provides a relatively long-term (5 days) atmospheric pressure forecast.
　OpenWeatherMap is an overseas company, but it seems to cover Japanese cities to some extent.
　By specifying the obtained API key and the city name or latitude and longitude in the program, the graph of temperature and pressure is drawn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I started a blog</title>
      <link>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/2022/03/03/atfirst_en/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://1plus1is3.github.io/posts/2022/03/03/atfirst_en/</guid>
      <description>In February 2022, I launched my portfolio site while I was busy with the Applied Information Technology exam.
(The GitHub history is a bit strange because I updated it significantly in June 2022.)
　This is due to the fact that I was able to get a chance to stand up and meet with them. It was also a good opportunity to write code and use GitHub properly.
　The site has a fairly minimalist structure, with only the top page, an About page, and a Posts page, which is a blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>https://1plus1is3.github.io/abouten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://1plus1is3.github.io/abouten/</guid>
      <description>About  Name: Suhito Sagara Twitter: https://twitter.com/1plus1is__ (JP, EN ok) GitHub: https://github.com/1plus1is3/ Qiita: https://qiita.com/1plus1is3/ (only Japanese)(basically, records of problem solving) TryHackMe: https://tryhackme.com/p/1plus1is3 HackTheBox: 1plus1is3 (Haven&amp;rsquo;t done much lately&amp;hellip;) CryptoHack: https://cryptohack.org/user/1plus1is3/ Portfolio Site: https://1plus1is3.github.io/ (here!)  Profile  Computer Science (Master degree, 2021) Cryptography (Post-Quantum Cryptography; Lattice, SIDH) Programming (Python, Go, C) (HTML&amp;amp;CSS, PHP)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>